<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Inspiration | Kinopyo Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/categories/inspiration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-29T17:35:43+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://kinopyo.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qihuan Piao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Take on Google I/O 2013 Keynote]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/my-take-on-google-io-2013-keynote/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-19T07:52:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/my-take-on-google-io-2013-keynote</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><div class='embed tweet'><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="ja"><p>Can't believe that I watched the 3.5 hours long keynote video of Google I/O 2013 <a href="https://t.co/mBj3E6pB4q" title="https://developers.google.com/events/io/">developers.google.com/events/io/</a></p>&mdash; kinopyoさん (@fantasyday) <a href="https://twitter.com/fantasyday/status/335721881887989760">2013年5月18日</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></p>

<p>Yesterday I was trying to catch up with the Google I/O 2013 to see what’s new. After I read some wrap up articles like <a href="http://thenextweb.com/insider/2013/05/15/everything-announced-at-the-google-io-2013-keynote-in-one-handy-list/">Everything announced at the Google I/O 2013 keynote in one handy list - The Next Web</a>, I was very intrigued and ended up watching the whole 3.5 hours long keynote video.</p>

<p>Given that I’m not an Android user or developer, I still felt the improvements on Android system quite impressive. But my biggest inspriation is not on any specific topic, it’s how Google thinks of solving problem in the terms of technolodgy, not just web or mobile, they always think in a big picture. Much bigger than I do.</p>

<p>I’ve been a web developer for over 5 years and now I do feel I’ve got a handy toolkit to solve some problems. But I also feel I’ve constrained myself to this area, limited my imagination. Anything that can’t solve with the skills I’ve got is impossible. Web is bigger than I perceived, and yet it is just a part of technolodgy. We all know that it’s just a tool to solve problems, not the only way to do it.</p>

<p>I need to think out of the box. It’s too comfortable to just sit there and see their innovations, instead of trying to be the guy on the stage to amaze people with your innovations. I’ve spent less and less time on predicting the future of the technolodgy, but more and more on reality issues, like where to live, when to get married or so. I guess that’s the inevitable trend as you getting old but at least I shouldn’t let what I’ve learned blind myself. Keep looking, don’t settle.</p>

<p>I’d like to end this post with the quote of Steve Jobs.</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.kinopyo.com/images/stay_hungry_stay_foolish.jpg" alt="Stay hungry, stay foolish" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
