<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Pow | Kinopyo Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/categories/pow/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-29T17:35:43+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://kinopyo.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qihuan Piao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Set Project Specific Environment Variables with Pow]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/setup-project-specific-environment-variables-with-pow/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-01T21:56:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/setup-project-specific-environment-variables-with-pow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In your rails app, when you need an envionment variable like <code>ENV['TWITTER_CONSUMER_KEY']</code> for local deveopment, where do you put them? Simply set them before you start your rails server as a one time thing, or just put them under ~/.profile or ~/.zshrc?</p>

<p>Well it works but I'm not happy with that. Because first it belongs to a specific project and expose them to global env make me feel a little bit uncomfortable, second, what if you happend to have more than one twitter integrated app, how do you name the variables to solve naming collision?</p>

<p>If you're using <a href="http://pow.cx">Pow</a>, there is a perfect solution for you.</p>

<h2>.powrc and .powenv</h2>

<p>Pow provides these 2 files for you to config pow and setup any environment variables.</p>

<blockquote><p>Before an application boots, Pow attempts to execute two scripts — first .powrc, then .powenv — in the application's root. Any environment variables exported from these scripts are passed along to Rack.</p></blockquote>

<p>Convention here is putting <code>.powrc</code> under git version control, and override or setup any project specific environment variables to <code>.powenv</code>.</p>

<h2>Let's do it</h2>

<p><code>diff .gitignore
+ .powenv
</code></p>

<p><code>ruby .powenv
export TWITTER_CONSUMER_KEY=foo
export TWITTER_CONSUMER_SECRET=bar
</code></p>

<p>BTW, you must run this command to restart pow manually so these scripts will be loaded.</p>

<p><code>
$ touch ~/.pow/restart.txt
</code></p>

<p><a href="http://pow.cx/manual.html#section_2.2">Pow Document: Customizing Environment Variables</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
