<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: dairy | Kinopyo Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/categories/dairy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-15T20:49:53+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://kinopyo.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qihuan Piao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sayonara, take care, be happy, forget me]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/sayonara%2C-take-care%2C-be-happy%2C-forget-me/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:31:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/sayonara,-take-care,-be-happy,-forget-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, I said the word.</p>

<p>It's painful, 6 years, it's not that easy, I cried a lot, I hope I made the right decision eventually, for her, for me.</p>

<p>I've drinked a lot, compared to my normal beer amount or capacity, I don't know the correct English, but it seems I'm still very clear, I guess I just need more.</p>

<p>I'm foolish, actually I have no idea how much I loved her, although I complains time to time, SHE IS THE ONE. I'M VERY SURE. Just I figured out so late.</p>

<p>I've deleted my facebook account. Because I know I'm gonna check her status, call her if she is unhappy, if she is painful. I can't delete my twitter account now, says "Twitter is over capacity.". Is there so many people breaking up and want to delete their accounts? Perfect!</p>

<p>I also decide to throw my phone away, iPhone, entiery. The reason is the same. I know I'm gonna check her status, looking forward to her iMessage. Like the lyrics, "It's a big big world I'm a little little girl", what if she losts herself? I was supposed to be there, around her, supports her. But I failed, admit, suck it.</p>

<p>I've got these feelings about modern communication. I prefer old schools, either we have a face to face conversation, or just go back to sending mails and waiting for days to receive the response.</p>

<p>Part of me I hope she can see this post, I'm still believing we can be together, can have a happy life, can move on. But another part of me don't hope that, cuz this will hurt her again. We've suffered enough. What a Hypocrite I am.</p>

<p>I regret, for my entire life, this this the only thing that I have to admit that I truly regret. There is no second chance.</p>

<p>宝宝，I'm not sure what will happen in the future. But if you're tired, someone make you heartbroken, if I'm still single, please let me know, please, please come back. I'll be there.</p>

<p>I promise.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
