<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Apple | Kinopyo Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-13T15:27:07+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://kinopyo.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qihuan Piao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When to Buy a New iPad, iPhone or Macbook]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/when-to-buy-a-new-ipad-iphone-or-macbook/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-16T21:50:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/when-to-buy-a-new-ipad-iphone-or-macbook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I gave my iPad to my mom when I went back to China during the golden week, so I'm wondering if now is a good timing to buy a new iPad? Are they going to release a new model soon? "Buy or wait", that's the only options for me every time when I think about any product of Apple.</p>

<h2>Macrumors Buyers Guide</h2>

<p>Then I found this <a href="http://buyersguide.macrumors.com/">buyersguide</a> by Macrumors. I know Macrumors website for a long time and used to subscribe to their RSS feeds, but I never noticed they have a this website.</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.kinopyo.com/images/macrumors_buyers_guide.png" alt="Macrumors Buyers Guide" /></p>

<p>Here you can see each Apple model with red or yellow round buttons. I guess there'll be green ones once the "timing" is right to buy that product. As it says:</p>

<blockquote><p>provide our best recommendations regarding current product cycles, and to provide a summary of currently available rumors for each model. This page is based on rumors and speculation and we provide no guarantee to its accuracy.</p></blockquote>

<h2>When to Buy a New iPad</h2>

<p>If you click the iPad link you'll see this:</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.kinopyo.com/images/when_to_buy_a_new_ipad.png" alt="When to Buy a New iPad" /></p>

<p>You can see the last release was October 23, 2012. Average
release cycles is 311 days so statistically there are still around 100 days left, but judging from the recent releases it could be next month! Recent rumors might be helpful, to at least give you something to fill in the blankness of waiting.</p>

<p>Maybe this time I'll give iPad mini a try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
