<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | Kinopyo Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-23T18:28:21+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://kinopyo.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qihuan Piao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recover Your Local Octopress Repository]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/recover-your-local-octopress-repository/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T01:52:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/recover-your-local-octopress-repository</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here I'll show you how to recover or restore your local octopress
repository, for instance you're on a new machine, or just lost your
local copy of it.</p>

<p>It requries you to have a repository on github that you've deployed your
octopress posts.</p>

<p>First I recommend that you read this post: <a href="http://blog.zerosharp.com/clone-your-octopress-to-blog-from-two-places/">Clone Your Octopress to Blog From Two Places</a>, the <strong>Recreating a local Octopress repository</strong> section.</p>

<p>And here is what worked for me, please replace <code>kinopyo</code> with your user
name.</p>

<p>```
git clone -b source git@github.com:kinopyo/kinopyo.github.com.git octopress
cd octopress</p>

<p>gem install bundler
bundle install</p>

<p>rake preview
open http://localhost:4000
```</p>

<h2>Tips on Converting HTML to Markdown</h2>

<p>Somehow the latest 3 posts are still missing after I git cloned my
remote repository. I checked in advance and saved those copies as html.
And after I restored my octopress repository I used <a href="http://johnmacfarlane.net/pandoc/">Pandoc</a> to convert those html to markdown.</p>

<p>It works like:</p>

<p><code>
pandoc -f html -t markdown your_html_file.html
</code></p>

<h2>Thoughts on Disaster</h2>

<p>p.s. I stored my blog octopress repository on Dropbox and somehow it
just all gone, it really shocked me. Probably it was my fault not
theirs, but still I always thought Dropbox is a safe place, but I don't
even have a clue why it happended and somehow could't see the history and
restore from their website. After I noticed it everytime I came up with
something to write I've had used it as an excuse, or maybe I was not in
the mood to deal with it(also I didn't know how...).</p>

<p>So I need a fallback solution about Dropbox, every disaster changes you to rethink
about current seems comfortable situation. And hope I'll write more often :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
