<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Link | Kinopyo Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/categories/link/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-19T09:44:22+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://kinopyo.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qihuan Piao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LINK: The first step is to start]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/link%3A-the-first-step-is-to-start/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-10T01:42:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/link:-the-first-step-is-to-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Off the topic</h2>

<p>Sometimes when I find something in the internet that is really interesting and inspiring, normally I'd like to write a blog post about it, but then I may get lazy and just somehow give up or totally forget it. That's one thing I want to improve.</p>

<p>So from today I'm gonna try this "light weight" post, just share a link and perhaps plus one phrase of my comment. Sure it could be done in a tweet, but I just wanna keep it in my blog.</p>

<h2>The first step is to start</h2>

<p><a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2538-the-first-step-is-to-start">The first step is to start by Jason Z. of 37signals</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Many times the reasons we don’t start something have nothing to do with lack of skills, materials, or facilities. The real blockers are self-criticism and excuses.</p></blockquote>

<p>Totally non related to the quote above...but if you read the link you'll understand what am I talking about next..</p>

<p>When I was a child I used to draw a lot, I still remember an afternoon in Summer I just sit there and kept drawing for 5 hours, I was completely in the "flow", if I put it in the current popular terms, and totally forgot how could time pass so fast. I also organized an event to get my friends together in a weekend to draw together, at that time I was trying to draw my own manga story of Doraemon. But when passing into adolescence I didn't remember why but somehow I stopped drawing.</p>

<p>Oops that is more than "one phrase" =_=;;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
