<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: diary | Kinopyo Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/categories/diary/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kinopyo.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-08T12:10:26+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://kinopyo.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qihuan Piao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My New Blog with Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/my-new-blog-with-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-31T22:49:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/my-new-blog-with-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally migrated all my posts from Wordpress to Octopress. I think it's quite popular among hackers and geeks these days, if you don't know it just google it, tons of results.</p>

<p>There're still a lot of works to do, like some posts with messy format or broken links, Disqus comments need to be migrated, categories are nonsense etc, but I'll announce this anyway. Done is better than perfect right?</p>

<p>I'm not gonna mention any migration details here, I'd like to look back and have a summary or something now.</p>

<h1>Over 300 posts since 2009/10/07</h1>

<p>I'm really surprised by myself. I was not aware of that I've done so many writings, and these're only published ones(I have a lot of drafts). Even though many of them are just simple code gist and programming related.</p>

<p>It's so easy now to "execute" an action to a resource. Like a photo, favourite a tweet or even +1 a youtube movie. So our foot prints or activities are spread everywhere and some of them might be important or meaningful to you, that just a light-single-built-in action is not enough. I want to keep those non-physical, intangible but essential "things" here, as part of my life.</p>

<h1>Japanese, English and Chinese</h1>

<p>There was a time I was trying to write down every single post in these 3 languages. I believe the plugin I used in Wordpress is called <em>qTranslate</em>, which let you write with each language or all of them.</p>

<p>After a while I noticed it was too hard for me. Translating same contents into a different language is boring and wasting of time, at least I tried and found out it doesn't work for me. So this time, I want this blog to be an English mainly blog, with occasional different language posts. My plan is writing emotional feelings in Chinese, and social activities or something related to Japan in Japanese.</p>

<p>I'm still keeping those language mixed posts here even though I think it's not useful to my "readers", not sure how many I got, I'd like to take those posts as old-days foot prints. "あの時がんばったな！ー" hehe.</p>

<h1>About the priority or weight of each language</h1>

<p>I want to be a top player in this programming field. In order to achieve that English is a MUST condition. I still remember when I first time read a programming book in English, it was so difficult that I hardly understood the meanings. But I keep trying and trying, now I'm very comfortable with it and believe it's more natural than any other language in programming field.</p>

<p>Besides the effort I put in English, I also want to start writing in my native language, Chinese. Although English is more friendly to me than before, it's still difficult to describe my feelings and emotions precisely. I need more vocabularies. I need to look back to think about if there is a grammar mistake. So when I think about some topics such as meanings of life, or what I want to left to the world, am I making this world a little bit better, etc. In these cases I need to grab my most familiar weapon :)</p>

<p>For Japanese, hmmm.. I'll leave it for now :)</p>

<h1>Google Adsense</h1>

<p>If you're an old readers of me, I hope you are, you may notice that there's no ads anymore. Yeah I used to put those ads for experiment. With 500-600 daily PVs, it gave me around 4,000￥ every month. Not that much but it's better than nothing, so I kept ads for a long time. But to be honest, as a personal blog it's just annoying. I didn't like it personally, and it's for sure it gives people bad impression, I don't like to miss a job opportunity if some head hunters open my blog and leave with a "WTF?!..".</p>

<p>Let's just be simple and clean.</p>

<p>That's it~ see you next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[採用観点から見たいいブログとは]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/good-blog-in-the-head-hunter-point-of-view"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/good-blog-in-the-head-hunter-point-of-view</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>この間仕事の関係でたくさんの技術者のブログを見たことがあって、自見ですが、採用の観点から見たときにどういうブログがよかったのか、正確に言うと採用に欲しい情報が探しやすいのかを整理したいと思いいます。</p>

<p>私自身はエンジニアで採用関連の仕事はほとんど未経験なので、プロの意見ではなく、あくまで自分が仕事の中で感じたことを書いただけです。ご参考までに。</p>

<h1>レイアウト</h1>

<p>ブログにアクセスしたときは私はまず「About」ページを見つけようとしました。実際の記事とかサイドバーの内容とかよりも、一般的には「About」ページでより詳しい、採用観点からの欲しい情報が得られるからです。なのでこの「自己紹介」のページへのリンクが見やすいかどうかが重要だと思います。</p>

<p>下にスクロールせずに見られる場所、例えばトップのタブバーとかにあれば助かります。</p>

<h1>Aboutページ</h1>

<p>多分ブロガーは誰もがこのAboutページを持っていると思いますが、「誰に向けて発信しているか？」が明確でないとなかなかいい文章にはならないと思います。</p>

<p>私も今まで自分のAboutページを本当適当に書いていて、「どうせ誰も見てないだろう」と思ってずっと更新すらしなかったですが、今回の仕事でわかったのが「採用/転職のチャンスを見逃したかも」ってことです。準備すらしなければ、実際チャンスにめぐり合った時もそのまま捕まえることができないです。</p>

<p>自分のAboutページは実際Google Analyticsで見たときはちょこちょこクリック率があることはわかってますが、本当に手抜き状態にしたまま。。too lazyですね！</p>

<h2>Aboutページで必要な情報</h2>

<p>ではこのAboutページで一体どんな情報があればいいのか？
+  簡単な自己紹介
+  言語（できれば英語版のも欲しい）
+  今の居場所（意外と重要）
+  スキル
+  今までの作品や成果、オープンソースへの貢献など
+  どういうことに興味があるか？どんなものが作りたいのか？
+  ソーシャルアカウント(Linkedin, Twitter, Github)
+  連絡先（メールアドレス）</p>

<p>自分の母国語以外に英語バージョンのも用意して欲しいですね。グローバル採用の流れで、本人も世界を目指すならばできれば絶対英語をオススメします。記事はまだ母国語でもいいですが。
Linkedinへのリンクがあれば一番助かります。
Githubでは持っているリポジトリ（Forkしたのも大丈夫）でどんな分野の技術に興味が有るのかをチェックして、フォローされた数も参考にしました。
Facebookは逆にあっても全然チェックする気がないです。
今の居場所は実際にFace to Faceで話したい時に会える距離であるかの参考になります。</p>

<h1>ブログ記事については</h1>

<p>ブログ記事は一個一個チェックしないですが、あまりにも更新がない（年に3〜4回とか）ブログは「あれ？放棄状態？」な心配がありそこの情報が信用できるかが疑われます。</p>

<h1>オススメトール</h1>

<p><a href="http://about.me">http://about.me</a>のサイトがありますが、ブログのAboutページをこれにしてもいいと思います。見た目が綺麗ですし、ソーシャルアカウントへのリンクも簡単に付けられて書く側も見る側も楽です。</p>

<p>さて、この記事を読んで自分のブログを見直したい方はいらっしゃるのかな？</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[楽天、アマゾン、Yahooなどを一括検索できるサイト]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/search-for-rakuten-amazon-yahoo"/>
    <updated>2011-11-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/search-for-rakuten-amazon-yahoo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>使ったことはないけど、とりあえずリストアップ。</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://all-search.biz/index.php">http://all-search.biz/index.php</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.tsukaerusite.com/">http://www.tsukaerusite.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.shopping-tool.com/">http://www.shopping-tool.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://aucfan.com/">http://aucfan.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://psearch.yahoo.co.jp/search/advanced">http://psearch.yahoo.co.jp/search/advanced</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone水没記、液晶交換で復活]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/iphone-dropped-in-water"/>
    <updated>2011-06-18T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/iphone-dropped-in-water</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>一ヶ月前の話ですが、iPhoneをお風呂に落としてしまいました。。。2、3秒くらいですかね。</p>

<p>液晶が点灯しなかったものの、まだ生きてます。
急いで電源を切りました。スワイプのジェスチャーがなかなか効かないので何回かやったんです。</p>

<p>そこでググってみてこんな措置をとりました。
+  本体は振ってはいけない
+  ドライヤーで乾かす
+  米に埋める(乾燥剤がなかった)
+  乾燥剤とiPhoneをジップロックに入れて待つ！
+  毎晩一回起動して様子を観察</p>

<p>それで、ほぼ4-5日経って特に変わりがなかったです。
(まだ液晶が点灯しない、バッテリとかその他は問題ない)
画面が暗いまま1週間使い続けてもう待てないと思って
ソフトバンクの店舗にいって正直に言いました。
思ったとおり検査で水没のセンサは反応あり、
修理はできず22,800¥で交換するしかないと言われました。</p>

<p>そんな時にTwitter<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/spdshinjuku">スマートフォンドクター新宿店</a>から連絡がきましたので、
お店にいって液晶だけ交換することにしました。
その場でTwitterでつぶやけばツイッター割があります。
合わせて8,800¥でした。ありがとうございました。</p>

<p>今まで問題なく使いました。大事にしないと。。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evernote,Twitterとブログ]]></title>
    <link href="http://kinopyo.com/blog/evernote-twitter-and-blog"/>
    <updated>2011-04-22T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://kinopyo.com/blog/evernote-twitter-and-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Evernote使い始めたのは結構前ですが、ちゃんとノートブックを整理してライフログ始めたのはまだこの二ヶ月の話です。
それからなかなかブログ更新するきっかけが少なくなりましたね。ただ教訓としてメモするのは基本Evernoteに蓄積してるし、普段思いついたものやストレス、情報共有とかは随時Twitterにつぶやくようになりました。</p>

<p>まあ、Evernote書いたメモって共有する価値はあるといえばありますが、何だかんだ重複作業になるような気がして抑えてはいます。またEvernoteって、基本自分向けなので気軽に書けるメリットもありますし、仕事が忙しくなったら本当にEvernoteに書くのも精一杯になりますからね。
と言ってもブログ書かないのは、それなりのインプットがないことと思いますよ。この業界で働いているなら、絶対これだけたみんなに伝えたいくらいの出来事はあるでしょうと思います。自分と同じような誤りや遠回しは避けて欲しいぐらい。
そういう意味ではちゃんと反省しないといけないと思いますよ、ここ最近の仕事とプライベートを。ただ疲れたを言い訳にしてないか、あるいは勉強不足でインプットが足りないかって。</p>

<p>酒飲んで調子に乗っていろいろ書いたけど、本当反省&amp;改善したい。</p>

<p>最後に、
この記事もiPhone FastEverって書いてます。いや〜本当に便利！チェックなしで発信！</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
